MUHAMMAD ZIAD ABUSAA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

+12 years experience of software development and +5 years of experience in DevOps and Cloud technologies. Well-versed in technology to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Skilled leader who has the proven ability to motivate, educate, and manage a team of professionals to build applications and effectively track changes.

WORK HISTORY

PRINCIPAL DEVOPS ENGINEER **SAUDI DIGITAL BANK**

1/1/2022 - Present



1/9/2019 - 30/12/2021



1/1/2018 - 1/8/2019

TECHNICAL TEAM LEADER, NETWAYS, RIYADH

1/1/2017 - 30/12/2017

SENIOR SOLUTION DESIGNER, NETWAYS, RIYADH

1/12/2012 – 1/1/2017

1/1/2010 - 30/11/2012

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, OGER SYSTEMS, RIYADH

Argo CD Essential Guide for End Users (Udemy)

PUBLISHED COURSES





net ays

net & ays

net ays



CERTIFICATIONS

Cloud Digital Leader

Certification Number: xvCjoH



CKA: Certified Kubernetes

Administrator

Certification Number: LF-kg8hjq9m42

CKS: Certified Kubernetes Security

Specialist

CERTIFICATION NUMBER: LF-IJ4BDLK3O6

CKAD: Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

Certification Number: LF-4xr63e8hp8

Microsoft Certified: DevOps

Engineer Expert

Certification Number: H584-3759

Microsoft Certified: Azure

Developer Associate

Certification Number: H584-3619

Microsoft® Certified Solutions

Expert: Productivity

Certification Number: G421-5726

Microsoft® Certified Solutions

Associate: Office 365

Certification Number: G421-5525

Microsoft Certified Professional

Certification Number: E933-3478

















SKILLS

- Containers orchestration / Kubernetes. "CKA, CKS and CKAD"
- Google Cloud: Cloud Digital Leader
- Azure DevOps. "Certified"
- Helm Charts: Building and maintaining.
- GitOps: Argo CD
- Teleport for PAM
- Building IaC using Terraform.
- Version control systems such as Azure DevOps and Gitlab.
- Secrets management using Vault

- Kubernetes management and monitoring: Rancher / Prometheus / Grafana.
- Team management / leadership
- .NET Core / Framework.
- Client Side Development
- SharePoint "Certified"
- Office 365 Understanding
- CRM Understanding
- BizTalk Understanding
- K2 Understanding
- Angular
- Project Scoping
- Application design
- Preparing demos and related presentation
- Product owner / scrum master / solution management
- System / Business analysis

PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

PLATFORM AND TRANSFORMATION

- Building production ready platform around cloud native ecosystem.
- Building Toolchain for DevSecOps.
 - Git and CI & CD tools.
 - Monitoring tools.
 - Secrets management tools.
 - Security tools for DevSecOps.
- Leading organization transformation using cloud native ecosystem.
- Applying security best practices related to systems, clusters and applications.
- Built multiple k8s clusters managed and "self hosted" for multi environments including production environment.

Page | 3 Muhammad Ziad Abusaa

INTERNET AND ESERVICES PROJECTS

- Amaaly: .NET Core / Docker / Kubernetes.
- Ministry of commerce / Franchise : .NET Core / Angular
- Ministry of commerce / Maroof : .NET Core / Docker and Kubernetes .
- SFDA eservices project : .Net Core , Kubernetes , React
- Ministry of interior Mifon Project : Angular JS , Web Api , SharePoint , CRM
- GMCO internet website : SharePoint 2013 , Word Automation
- The centennial fund eServices website (eServices using .Net)
- Alrajhi Takaful Internet website (eServices using .Net)
- Council of Saudi Chambers Internet website : SharePoint 2010
- High Commission for the Development of Arrivadh website: SharePoint 2010

ERP

• RDCCI ERP web application (using asp.net web forms)

INTRANET PROJECTS

- Sanabil Intranet: SharePoint 2016 / CMS
- SASO Intranet: SharePoint 2010 / .Net / AngularJs / K2
- Ecra intranet: SharePoint 2013 / Word Automation
- GMCO intranet : SharePoint 2013 / CMS
- COE enterprise content management system : SharePoint
- AlSubaie intranet : SharePoint 2010
- Riyadh Chamber of Commerce Intranet: SharePoint 2010

EDUCATION

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF JORDAN, AMMAN

2005- 2009

Page | 4 Muhammad Ziad Abusaa